if we now just have a rapid look at the different
services of an operating system we can see
that there are parts of the operating system
that are above the system calls so you don't
really need to interact with the hardware
the graphical user interface for example
here is an example and parts that are below
so the file system when you want to store/open
a file and this kind of things you need to actually
interact with the disk so this stays
let's say below the level of the system calls
there are parts of the operating system that
are there for the user to basically interact
with the hardware so you can run programs
that you need to read from the disk you can
communicate with devices you can access files
and so on
there are parts of the operating system that
are actually about dealing with errors
a connection failure so if you try to attempt to read a
part of memory
you don't have the right to read
and of course there are parts of the operating
system that are for the operating system itself
to be efficient to decide which processes
to run to protect the memory of a user
from other users and so on and so forth